Part 1. A Child at Gateshead.
第一部分. 在盖茨黑德的孩子.
Chapter 1. The Red Room.
第一章. 红房子.
We could not go for a walk that afternoon.
那天下午我们不能去散步.
There was such a freezing cold wind and such heavy rain that we all stayed indoors.
因为寒风凛冽，暴雨倾盆，我们都待在室内.
I was glad of it. I never liked long walks, especially in winter.
我很高兴. 我从不喜欢长时间的散步，尤其是在冬天.
I used to hate coming home when it was almost dark, with ice-cold fingers and toes,
我讨厌在天快黑时回家，手指和脚趾冻得冰冷，
feeling miserable because Bessie, the nursemaid, was always scolding me.
感到沮丧，因为保姆贝西总是责骂我.
All the time I knew I was different from my cousins, Eliza, John and Georgiana Reed.
我一直知道我和我的表兄妹们不同，伊丽莎、约翰和乔治亚娜·里德.
They were taller and stronger than me, and they were loved.
他们比我高大强壮，并且被宠爱.
These three usually spent their time crying and quarrelling,
这三个人通常花时间哭闹和争吵，
but today they were sitting quietly around their mother in the sitting room.
但今天他们安静地坐在客厅里陪着母亲.
I wanted to join the family circle, but Mrs. Reed, my aunt, refused.
我想加入他们的家庭圈子，但我的姨妈里德夫人拒绝了.
Bessie had complained about me.
贝西对我有抱怨.
No, I'm sorry, Jane. Until I hear from Bessie or see for myself that you are really trying to behave better,
“不，抱歉，简。直到我听到贝西的话或亲眼看到你确实在努力改善行为，
you cannot be treated as a good, happy child like my children.
你不能像我的孩子们一样被当作一个好孩子对待。”
What does Bessie say I have done? I asked.
“贝西说我做了什么？” 我问.
Jane, it is not polite to question me in that way. If you cannot speak pleasantly, be quiet.
“简，这样质问我是不礼貌的。如果你不能礼貌地说话，就保持安静。”
I crept out of the sitting room and into the small room next door,
我悄悄地走出客厅，进入隔壁的小房间，
where I chose a book full of pictures from the bookcase.
从书架上选择了一本充满图片的书.
I climbed onto the window seat and drew the curtains, so that I was completely hidden.
我爬上窗台，拉上窗帘，使我完全隐蔽.
I sat there for a while.
我在那里坐了一会儿.
Sometimes I looked out of the window at the grey November afternoon
有时我从窗户望出去，看到灰色的十一月下午，
and saw the rain pouring down on the leafless garden.
雨水倾泻在无叶的花园里.
But most of the time I studied the book and stared fascinated at the pictures.
但大多数时候我在看书，对图片感到着迷.
Lost in the world of imagination, I forgot my sad, lonely existence for a while and was happy.
沉浸在想象的世界中，我暂时忘记了自己悲惨孤独的存在，感到快乐.
I was only afraid that my secret hiding place might be discovered.
我只怕我的秘密藏身之处可能会被发现.
Suddenly, the door of the room opened. John Reed rushed in.
突然，房间的门打开了。约翰·里德冲了进来.
Where are you, rat? he shouted. He did not see me behind the curtain.
“你在哪里，老鼠？” 他喊道. 他没有看到我在窗帘后面.
Eliza, Georgie, Jane isn't here. Tell Mama she's run out into the rain.
“伊丽莎、乔治，简不在这里。告诉妈妈她跑出去淋雨了。”
What a bad animal she is.
“她真是个坏动物。”
How lucky I drew the curtain, I thought.
“幸好我拉上了窗帘，” 我想.
He would never have found me because he was not very intelligent.
他永远也找不到我，因为他不太聪明.
But Eliza guessed at once where I was.
但伊丽莎立刻猜到我在哪里.
She's in the window seat, John, she called from the sitting room.
“她在窗台上，约翰，” 她从客厅里喊道.
So I came out immediately, as I did not want him to pull me out.
于是我立刻出来了，因为我不想让他把我拉出来.
What do you want? I asked him.
“你想要什么？” 我问他.
Say, what do you want, Master Reed? he answered, sitting in an armchair.
“说，‘你想要什么，里德少爷？’” 他回答，坐在一把扶手椅上.
I want you to come here.
“我要你到这儿来。”
John Reed was 14 and I was only 10. He was large and rather fat.
约翰·里德14岁，我只有10岁。他又高又胖.
He usually ate too much at meals, which made him ill.
他通常在餐时吃得太多，这让他生病.
He should have been at boarding school, but his mother, who loved him very much,
他本该在寄宿学校，但他的母亲非常爱他，
had brought him home for a month or two because she thought his health was delicate.
因为她认为他的健康很脆弱，所以把他接回家住一个月或两个月.
John did not love his mother or his sisters, and he hated me.
约翰不爱他的母亲或姐妹，他讨厌我.
He bullied and punished me, not two or three times a week, not once or twice a day, but all the time.
他欺负和惩罚我，不是一周两三次，不是一两次，而是一直这样.
My whole body trembled when he came near.
当他靠近时，我全身都在颤抖.
Sometimes he hit me, sometimes he just threatened me,
有时他打我，有时只是威胁我，
and I lived in terrible fear of him. I had no idea how to stop him.
我生活在对他的恐惧中，不知道如何制止他.
The servants did not want to offend their young master,
仆人们不愿得罪他们的小主人，
and Mrs. Reed could see no fault in her dear boy.
而里德夫人看不到她亲爱的儿子有任何错误.
So I obeyed John's order and approached his armchair,
所以我听从约翰的命令，走近他的扶手椅，
thinking how very ugly his face was.
想着他的脸是多么丑陋.
Perhaps he understood what I was thinking, for he hit me hard on the face.
也许他明白我在想什么，因为他狠狠打了我一拳.
That is for your rudeness to Mama just now, he said,
“这是为了你刚才对妈妈的无礼，” 他说，
and for your wickedness in hiding, and for looking at me like that, you rat!
“以及你躲起来的邪恶，还有你看我的眼神，老鼠！”
I was so used to his bullying that I never thought of hitting him back.
我习惯了他的欺负，从未想过还击.
What were you doing behind that curtain? he asked.
“你在窗帘后面做什么？” 他问.
I was reading, I answered. Show me the book. I gave it to him.
“我在看书，” 我回答. “把书给我。” 我把书给了他.
You have no right to take our books, he continued.
“你没有权利拿我们的书，” 他继续说.
You have no money, and your father left you none.
“你没有钱，你的父亲也没给你留下任何钱.
You ought to beg in the streets, not live here in comfort with a gentleman's family.
你应该在街上乞讨，而不是在这里和一个绅士家庭一起舒适地生活.”
Anyway, all these books are mine, and so is the whole house, or will be in a few years' time.
“无论如何，这些书都是我的，这整个房子也是我的，或者几年后会是我的.”
I'll teach you not to borrow my books again.
“我会教你不要再借我的书.”
He lifted the heavy book and threw it hard at me.
他举起沉重的书，狠狠地扔向我.
It hit me and I fell, cutting my head on the door.
书砸到了我，我跌倒了，头撞在门上.
I was in great pain, and suddenly, for the first time in my life, I forgot my fear of John Reed.
我感到剧痛，突然间，第一次，我忘记了对约翰·里德的恐惧.
You wicked, cruel boy, I cried. You are a bully.
“你这个邪恶残忍的男孩，” 我喊道. “你是个欺负人.”
You are as bad as a murderer.
“你和杀人犯一样坏。”
What? What, he cried? Did she say that to me? Did you hear Eliza and Georgiana?
“什么？什么？” 他喊道. “她对我这样说了吗？你们听见了吗，伊丽莎和乔治亚娜？”
I'll tell Mama, but first...
“我要告诉妈妈，但首先……”
He rushed to attack me, but now he was fighting with a desperate girl.
他冲上来攻击我，但现在他面对的是一个绝望的女孩.
I really saw him as a wicked murderer.
我真的把他看作一个邪恶的杀人犯.
I felt the blood running down my face, and the pain gave me strength.
我感觉到血从脸上流下来，疼痛给了我力量.
I fought back as hard as I could.
我尽力反抗.
My resistance surprised him, and he shouted for help.
我的抵抗让他吃惊，他喊叫求助.
His sisters ran for Mrs. Reed, who called her maid Miss Abbott and Bessie.
他的姐妹们跑去叫里德夫人，她叫来了她的女仆艾伯特小姐和贝西.
They pulled us apart, and I heard them say,
他们把我们分开，我听见他们说，
What a wicked girl! She attacked Master John!
“多么坏的女孩！她袭击了约翰少爷！”
Mrs. Reed said calmly, Take her away to the red room and lock her in there.
里德夫人平静地说：“把她带到红房子，把她锁在里面。”
And so I was carried upstairs, arms waving and legs kicking.
于是我被带上楼，双臂挥舞着，双腿踢打着.
As soon as we arrived in the red room, I became quiet again, and the two servants both started scolding me.
一到红房子，我又安静下来，两位仆人开始责骂我.
Really, Miss Eyre, said Miss Abbott, how could you hit him? He's your young master.
“真的，艾尔小姐，” 艾伯特小姐说，“你怎么能打他？他是你的少爷。”
How can he be my master? I'm not a servant, I cried.
“他怎么能是我的少爷？我不是仆人，” 我哭道.
No, Miss Eyre, you are less than a servant because you do not work, replied Miss Abbott.
“不，艾尔小姐，你比仆人还不如，因为你不工作，” 艾伯特小姐回答.
They both looked at me as if they strongly disapproved of me.
她们都以强烈的不赞成眼神看着我.
You should remember, Miss, said Bessie,
“你应该记住，小姐，” 贝西说，
that your aunt pays for your food and clothes, and you should be grateful.
“你的姨妈为你的食物和衣服付钱，你应该感激.”
You have no other relations or friends.
“你没有其他亲戚或朋友.”
All my short life I had been told this, and I had no answer to it.
“我短暂的一生中一直被告知这些，我无言以对.”
I stayed silent, listening to these painful reminders.
“我默默地听着这些痛苦的提醒.”
And if you are angry and rude, Mrs. Reed may send you away, added Bessie.
“如果你生气和无礼，里德夫人可能会把你送走，” 贝西补充道.
Anyway, said Miss Abbott, God will punish you, Jane Eyre, for your wicked heart.
“无论如何，” 艾伯特小姐说，“上帝会惩罚你，简·艾尔，为你的邪恶心灵.”
Pray to God and say you're sorry.
“向上帝祈祷并说对不起.”
They left the room, locking the door carefully behind them.
她们离开了房间，小心地锁上了门.
The red room was a cold, silent room, hardly ever used, although it was one of the largest bedrooms in the house.
红房子是一个寒冷、寂静的房间，几乎从未使用过，尽管它是房子里最大的卧室之一.
Nine years ago, my uncle, Mr. Reed, had died in this room, and since then, nobody had wanted to sleep in it.
九年前，我的叔叔里德先生在这个房间里去世，从那以后，没人愿意在这里睡觉.
Now that I was alone, I thought bitterly of the people I lived with.
现在我一个人，我苦涩地想着我与之同住的人.
John Reed, his sisters, his mother, the servants, they all accused me, scolded me, hated me.
约翰·里德，他的姐妹们，他的母亲，仆人们，他们都指责我，责骂我，恨我.
Why could I never please them?
“为什么我不能让他们满意？”
Eliza was selfish but was respected.
“伊丽莎自私，但受到尊重.”
Georgiana had a bad temper, but she was popular with everybody because she was beautiful.
“乔治亚娜脾气不好，但因为她漂亮，所以大家都喜欢她.”
John was rude, cruel, and violent, but nobody punished him.
“约翰粗鲁、残忍、暴力，但没有人惩罚他.”
I tried to make no mistakes, but they called me naughty every moment of the day.
“我尽量不犯错，但他们每时每刻都叫我淘气.”
Now that I turned against John to protect myself, everybody blamed me.
“现在我反抗约翰以保护自己，大家都责怪我.”
And so I spent that whole long afternoon in the red room,
“于是我整整一个漫长的下午都在红房子里度过，
asking myself why I had to suffer and why life was so unfair.
问自己为什么我必须受苦，为什么生活如此不公平.”
Perhaps I would run away or starve myself to death.
“也许我会逃跑，或者饿死自己.”
Gradually, it became dark outside.
渐渐地，外面变得黑暗.
The rain was still beating on the windows, and I could hear the wind in the trees.
雨仍然打在窗户上，我能听到树上的风声.
Now I was no longer angry, and I began to think the Reeds might be right.
“现在我不再生气，开始觉得里德家可能是对的.”
Perhaps I was wicked.
“也许我真的是邪恶的.”
Did I deserve to die and be buried in the churchyard like my Uncle Reed?
“我应该像我叔叔里德一样死去并被埋葬在教堂墓地吗？”
I could not remember him, but knew he was my mother's brother,
“我记不得他，但知道他是我母亲的兄弟，
who had taken me to his house when my parents both died.
在我父母都去世后把我带到他家.”
On his deathbed, he had made his wife, Aunt Reed, promise to look after me like her own children.
“在他临终时，他让他的妻子，也就是我的姨妈里德夫人，承诺像对待自己的孩子一样照顾我.”
I supposed she now regretted her promise.
“我想她现在后悔她的承诺了.”
A strange idea came to me.
“一个奇怪的想法突然出现.”
I felt sure that if Mr. Reed had lived, he would have treated me kindly.
“我确信如果里德先生还活着，他会善待我.”
And now, as I looked round at the dark furniture and the walls in shadow,
“现在，当我环顾四周，看着黑暗的家具和阴影中的墙壁，
I began to fear that his ghost might come back to punish his wife for not keeping her promise.
我开始害怕他的幽灵会回来惩罚他的妻子，因为她没有履行她的承诺.”
He might rise from the grave in the churchyard and appear in this room.
“他可能会从教堂墓地里爬出来，出现在这个房间里.”
I was so frightened by this thought that I hardly dared to breathe.
“这个念头让我如此害怕，我几乎不敢呼吸.”
Suddenly, in the darkness, I saw a light moving on the ceiling.
突然，在黑暗中，我看到天花板上有一道光移动.
It may have been from a lamp outside, but in my nervous state, I did not think of that.
“可能是外面的灯光，但在我紧张的状态下，我没想到这一点.”
I felt sure it must be a ghost, a visitor from another world.
“我确信这一定是鬼魂，一个来自另一个世界的访客.”
My head was hot. My heart beat fast.
“我的头很热. 我的心跳得很快.”
Was that the sound of wings in my ears? Was that something moving near me?
“那是我耳朵里的翅膀声吗？那是我身边有什么东西在动吗？”
Screaming wildly, I rushed to the door and shook it.
“我疯狂地尖叫，冲到门口，摇晃它.”
Miss Abbott and Bessie came running to open it.
艾伯特小姐和贝西跑来打开它.
Miss Eyre, are you ill? asked Bessie.
“艾尔小姐，你病了吗？” 贝西问.
Take me out of here! I screamed.
“带我出去！” 我尖叫.
Why? What's the matter? she asked.
“为什么？怎么了？” 她问.
I saw a light, and I thought it was a ghost, I cried, holding tightly onto Bessie's hand.
“我看到一道光，我以为是鬼魂，” 我哭道，紧紧握住贝西的手.
She's not even hurt, said Miss Abbott in disgust.
“她根本没受伤，” 艾伯特小姐厌恶地说.
She screamed just to bring us here.
“她只是为了让我们来这儿才尖叫.”
I know all our little tricks.
“我知道她的所有小把戏.”
What is all this? demanded an angry voice.
“这是怎么回事？” 一个愤怒的声音问.
Mrs. Reed appeared at the door of the room.
里德夫人出现在房间门口.
Abbott and Bessie, I think I told you to leave Jane Eyre in this room till I came.
“艾伯特和贝西，我想我告诉过你们把简·艾尔留在这个房间里，直到我来.”
She screamed so loudly, Mum, said Bessie softly.
“她喊得很大声，夫人，” 贝西轻声说.
Let go of her hands, Bessie, was Mrs. Reed's only answer.
“放开她的手，贝西，” 里德夫人唯一的回答.
Jane Eyre, you need not think you can succeed in getting out of the room like this.
“简·艾尔，你不必认为你可以通过这种方式成功地离开房间.”
Your naughty tricks will not work with me.
“你的淘气把戏对我不起作用.”
You will stay here an hour longer as a punishment for trying to deceive us.
“你将再待一个小时，作为惩罚，因为你试图欺骗我们.”
Oh, Aunt, please forgive me. I can't bear it.
“哦，姨妈，请原谅我。我不能忍受.”
I shall die if you keep me here.
“如果你把我留在这里，我会死.”
I screamed and kicked as she held me.
“我尖叫和踢打，她抓住我.”
Silence! Control yourself!
“安静！控制自己！”
She pushed me, resisting wildly, back into the red room and locked me in.
“她把我推回红房子，锁在里面.”
There I was in the darkness again with the silence and the ghosts.
“我又回到了黑暗中，和寂静和鬼魂在一起.”
I must have fainted. I cannot remember anything more.
“我一定是晕倒了。我记不清更多了.”